# Rickie H. Dixon Jr.

727-642-7851 | University Place, WA | rhdixon79@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Github | rickiedixon.com

#### SUMMARY

Adaptive full stack web developer with front and back end knowledge. Hard working and collaborative individual who is ready to bring an enthusiastic attitude to any work environment with a background in customer service and architectural design. These combined experiences help to bring a critical eye to new projects.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- React
- Java
- Python
- JavaScript

- HTML
- CSS
- MySQL
- MongoDB

- Django
- Spring
- Express.JS
- BootStrap

## TECHNICAL PROJECTS

## **Crwn Clothing** | React

- Website architected using React that leverages Firebase cloud firestore for backend support
- Google sign in integration for authorization and to ease facilitation of user information
- Leveraged Redux for a coherent global state for optimal performance, easy debugging and data persistence across multiple components

## Handy Helper | Python

- Application created using Django framework
- Utilizing CRUD commands jobs can be created, given away or deleted
- Users may also add jobs from other users to their own list of jobs and mark them as done once completed
- User access provided by Django-authentication to ensure protection of account

## **Study Buddy** | React

- A study timer created using React and Bootstrap based on the Pomodoro study technique
- Timer is equipped with standard functionality (i.e. start, stop and time increment/decrement/ reset)
- Users access their Spotify account (with Spotify API authenticate) to enjoy focus music while studying or working on a project

## **EDUCATION**

Coding Dojo | Full-Stack Developer Certificate | Bellevue, WA

• Immersive Full-Stack training program in Python, Java and MERN

2021

Saint Petersburg College | A.A. in Architectural Design | Saint Petersburg, FL

• Studied conceptual and practical application of architectural design

2008

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Bartender | The Matador | Tacoma, WA

2021-Present

- Increased bar sales 15% by upselling key menu items.
- Utilize multitasking skills by providing bar service and customer care in an efficient manner
- Provide training for multiple staff members ensuring adherence to established guidelines

# Bartender | Garage Bowl & Billiards | Seattle, WA

2016-2020

- Handled high volume bar with attention to detail
- Catered event hosting
- Keeping customer experience a top priority

# Carpenter | MESH, LLC. Architecture/Fabrication | Saint Petersburg, FL

2009-2016

- Read blueprints to compile cut list and check for adequate material inventory
- Assembled and installed custom cabinetry and furniture
- Responsibly delivered finished materials on schedule